Stephanie Japs

stephjaps@gmail.com | 612-306-3237 | Twin Cities, Minnesota

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-japs | Github: github.com/minnesotanice

Website: www.stephjaps.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced at working on projects from initial idea and development phase, performing all design/architecture work and delivering the completed product. Proven track record of excelling at learning new technologies and applying them to develop clean and well-structured code.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, SASS/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ColdFusion, Node.Js, Express, React.js, React Native, GIT, Github, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, the command line, computer science fundamentals, writing tests.

PROJECTS

Online Writing Journal | Handlebars.js, SCSS, Bootstrap | <u>Github</u> | <u>Live</u> Front End Developer Node/Express application where users log in, write components of a creative project, and save to a database.

Memory Game of Thrones | React.js, Bootstrap | Github | Live

Sole Developer

A memory game created with React.

Eat-Da-Burger | Node.js, Express.js, MySQL | Github | Live A burger logging app that follows the MVC design pattern.

Sole Developer

Bruce Springsteen Trivia | JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap | <u>Github</u> | <u>Live</u> Sole Developer Test your knowledge of Bruce Springsteen in a timed quiz. This game uses JavaScript for the logic and jQuery to manipulate HTML.

EXPERIENCE

NewBay Media 8/2014 - Present

Front End Developer

- Coded a third party web design into a pixel perfect, responsive site with ColdFusion, HTML5 and CSS. (www.AV-iQ.com).
- Set up SASS to easily customize colors and compress CSS for hundreds of product catalogs.
- Used SASS and ColdFusion to revise site for mobile friendliness. This revision included SASS variables and functions for customizing viewport breakpoints as well as SVG graphics with custom colors.
- Create interactive features using jQuery and Javascript.
- Mentored students to be quality Front End Developers.
- Prototype new website features with Photoshop, Illustrator and Adobe XD in conjunction with manipulating the DOM.
- All duties listed below from Web Designer position.

InfoComm International 10/2010 - 8/2014

Front End Developer

 AV-iQ was a division of InfoComm International until it was bought by NewBay Media in August of 2014. See job description above. InfoComm International 10/2004 - 10/2010

Web Designer

 Make companies product catalogs look and function seamlessly in client website designs using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ColdFusion.

- Prototype new website features with Photoshop, Illustrator and Fireworks in conjunction with manipulating the DOM.
- Create email templates for dynamic content that display well in a variety of email clients.
- Create banner ads.
- Optimize sites for all browsers.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities, MN

University of Minnesota Coding Boot Camp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js.

Metropolitan State University, Saint Paul, MN Self-Designed Degree in Computer Arts